May I come in sir?  Welcome.  Thank you sir.
Good morning sir.  Have your seat please.  Thank
you sir.
Yes Ghazal.  Are you ready for the interview?  Yes
sir.  Ok.  So we will be asking you a lot of
questions here.
Then
technical ok regarding HR questions
we expect you can speak in both
languages ​​Hindi as well as English yes sir are you
capable with both the languages ​​yes sir ok
so get ready for the questions ok sir so
good morning friends welcome to PD
classes today an important session for those who are
going for sales executive
interview and I hope
we have already given you abundant of sales executive related videos
friends you are
definitely watching those videos.  In today's interview session,
we are going to ask many new questions to our
candidates.  This is a mock
session.  I would like to tell all the students who are
going to our Skills Executive that
you can watch abundant of
videos regarding spoken English,
personality and body language on both our channels PD Classes and Intro Guide.   You
can learn a lot from there free of cost.  First of all I would like to welcome you
Ghazal.  Thank you sir.  Ghazal you who
want to come into the sales executive line.
Right?  And I have a pen right here.
So will you sell this pen?   Yes
sir.  Sure.  Let's
start your interview from here.  Okay sir,
first of all, its cap is very good
and it is from Cello company and it works very well
and is polite and it comes
in different colours, red, blue and black, good,
the cap is very politely, you can also change
its refill, okay, and what is its price, sir,
it is only ₹10, oh wow, it is such a cheap pen, that's
good, you can keep this pen, okay,
Ghazal, you tell us that if you are coming into sales, then
definitely you will know
what qualities a sales executive should have.  Yes
sir.  I would
like to say that first of all the sales executive should have
confidence.  Ok.  So are you
a confident girl?  Yes sir.  That's
good.  How your name matches your personality?   Yes
sir.  My name matches my personality as
I am a jewel and philanthropist girl.  Ok.
And what are your hobbies?  Sir my hobbies are
dancing and modelling.  Ok.  Look, you are
coming into dancing, you are coming into modelling.
So how is your people dealing?  What
kind of people do you like to deal with
?  Because people dealing within sales
is varied.  Yes sir.  I am a
versatile girl and if you are asking then
I would like to tell you that I like positive people
and versatile people too.  Ok.
So you are a positive attitude girl.  Yes sir.
Ok.  You stated in your strengths that you are
yourself is a positive attitude girl.   Yes
sir.  So what is your weakness?  Sir my
weakness is I am a very little talk girl.
Ok.  Now it is not a small matter.  Yes sir.  Ok.
Well, look at marketing jobs,
sales jobs, in this it is obvious that the
person should be a little talkative only.  Perhaps this
weakness of yours will be a great advantage for us.   Yes
sir.  Right.  Well, tell me whether you
like to work alone or in a team?
Sir, I prefer working alone
but I like team spirit more.
Ok.  This means you can also work in a team spirit.  Yes
sir.  And if you are given the
task of selling something alone, you can do it.  No
problem.  Ok.  That's good.  Well, tell me,
like for this job you may have to go to
different places.  So how will you
manage staying outside?  Yes sir I
can go from Kashmir to Kanyakumari even abroad
and I don't have homesickness.  Oh wow,
good Ghazal, do you have any job experience
related to sales?  Yes sir.  Ok.  Can you tell me something
about it?  Yes sir, I have
also done door to door sales of products and
I have also sold credit cards.   Have
you sold credit cards also?  Yes
sir.  That's very good.  And door to door selling is
also a bit tough job.  Yes sir.  Well,
see, you have sold credit cards, so the
customers are not made easily,
clients, I mean they do not agree easily, they do
not agree, yes sir, credit card job is a very tough job
too, but we tell them the
benefits, tell them the advantages
of that product, then they do not agree easily,
but we convince them, hey, this is what
management is required, these are the skills required in this job.
Okay, so you have those skills.  Yes sir.   That's
good.  Well, look Ghazal, you
know very well that when we advertise the job of a sales executive,
many
candidates come here.  So
give us some reason to select you.
Why should we select only you?  Sir,
first of all I have those skills.  I
can attract people towards me
and I am a bit talkative so people get
attracted to me.  Oh wow!  That means
we prefer you through conversation.  Yes
sir.  But why we select only you.  Aldo
at present I can't judge others.  Who are
standing in a queue like me?  But I can assure you about myself that I am a
punctual,
disciplined and confident girl.  That's
good.  And suppose you are not selected in this
interview then.  I believe in try try
again and I come to know about my weaknesses
and I will work on it and I will come again.  I would
love for you to come again for the interview.  Are
you that confident?  Yes sir.   Well,
this is a good thing.  See, selling job
is such a job where many times it happens
that you have to talk with the customer for long
hours.  You have to convince them, explain it to them
many times and even tell them the benefits and
advantages and they also
compare it with the competition.  Yes sir.  So
according to you, if there is a sales executive and
his sales are not good
then what should he do?  Meaning,
what kind of skills should he develop
?  First of all he should know how to talk to people and
explain things to them.
Understanding should be created among people that
this thing is good.  And along with this, one should have the ability to speak
and should know how to attract people.
This is what I believe.  Ok.  So
inside selling you believe that you must tell
the qualities and everything of a person.   That's
good.  Well, have you already got these things
inbuilt or have you learnt or
practiced them somewhere?  Sir it is inbuilt.  Oh
wow.  So you already had the experience.
How many years was that your experience?  More than
two years.  Hey, do you have more than two years of
experience?  That's good.  Ghazal,
look, you are coming to Sales Executive,
so let me put a situation in front of you.
The situation is that you have to
sell out a product or service and you have to do this
over the phone and the people you have to deal with, the people you have to
call, do not know you.
They are unknown to you.  Now if
you want to make them your customers, how will you talk to them?
How will you deal with them on the phone?  Sure sir.   First of all
I will tell them about my company.
I will tell you the good things about my company.  And then I will tell you about my product.  I
will tell you about the qualities of the product.  And then I will
ask him what he does?  He is working
, a student, a housewife or anything else, or a
businessman.  And then I will tell you
how that product will be useful to them?  Ok.
Meaning, according to the student,
what will come according to the student?  Yes sir.
What will happen according to the businessman?  Yes sir.
Ok.  That's wonderful.  You have given a very good answer.  Yes
sir.  Well, see, you
gave your best performance and the time has come.
Help our viewers too.  Stay
with us till the end.  Friends, if
you stay with us till the end, I will
give you a tip in the end.  Your tip is very
useful.  Look, here my first
question to Ghazal was that you want to sell
out the pen.  And if you give a startup in the startup that Ghazal had given, then the first thing
I would say is the same line that Ghazal
said, that Sir, first of all tell me about the company.
So it is obvious that when you are going to
sell out to someone, you will say
good morning sir.  If I do this selling on behalf of Ghazal then
I will say good
morning sir.  Sir I am Ghazal from Cello
company, Renals company whatever company you are
and after that you will tell the qualities of that pen.
Look here
two things are given very often during the interview.
Within selling skills or let's say
within sales executive interview.  Either
they give you a mobile or they
give you a pen.  I will
tell my students that you must complete these two topics.
Apart from this, you will do a
good SWOT analysis.  In this type of interview,
you are often asked about your salary expectations.
And if the answer to salary is
asked from Ghazal, Ghazal if you are told
that you are coming for sales executive
then how much salary do you want?  So
what will you say?  Sir, one has to deal with people
, travel around, explore things, and create
understanding among people.  So
according to me 30,000 plus, you said salary
sir, I don't want numbering.  So here I would
like to highlight to Ghazal as well as to my students that look,
you will not give numbering during the interview, friends.
You will always give diplomatic answers.  You will
say Sir salary is not the only essential
thing for me.  It is essential but not the only
essential thing for me.  Job Satisfaction
and Growth Opportunities R Morant.  However I am
sure if you make an offer it will be
equal to my qualifications and the current
salary structure of the industry.  And the
way Ghazal described the profile, that
profile is very hard, so obviously there should be
incentives as well, there should be salary as well
and you get perks etc separately,
so it is well and good and Ghazal you have given a very
good intro, good keep it up, you have given a very
good intro, good ok ok Ghazal your
intro is over now you can go, thank you sir